Guide to the Gerrit Lansing Papers YCAL MSS 469
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- August 2019 acquisition, 1814–2018; Bulk, 1950–2018; 8; 53.85 Linear Feet (66 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - General Correspondence
      - Sanders, Ed, undated (Box 17)
      - Sandy, Stephen, 2010–2012 (Box 17)
      - Sawyer-Lauçanno, Chris, and Patricia Pruitt, 1994 (Box 17)
      - Schelling, Andrew, 1988–1995 (Box 17)
      - Shearer, Branton, undated (Box 17)
      - Shepard, Joseph, 2013 (Box 17)
      - Shively, Charley, 2004–2017 (Box 17)
      - Shor, Mary, undated (Box 17)
      - Short, David, 1998-2003, undated (Box 17)
      - Sigo, Cedar, 2008 (Box 17)
      - Smith, Dale, and Hoa Nguyen, 1998–2010 (Box 17)
      - Smith, Pat, 1986–2005 (Box 17)
      - Smith, Philip, 2007 (Box 17)
      - Smoler, Michael, 1999 (Box 17)
      - Snowlake, Erica, 2004 (Box 17)
      - Sokolowski, Michael, 2007–2008 (Box 17)
      - Spears, Andre, 2015 (Box 17)
      - Stein, Charles, 1982–1993 (Box 17)
      - Sugden, Rick, 1981 (Box 17)
      - Tagett, Richard, 1999 (Box 18)
      - Tarn, Nathaniel, and Janet Rodney, 1977, undated (Box 18)
      - Thilleman, Tod, 2014 (Box 18)
      - Torra, Joseph, 1993-2000, undated (Box 18)
      - Tripp, Ben, 2010 (Box 18)
      - Tutko, Renata, 2017 (Box 18)
      - Valente, Peter, undated (Box 18)
      - Vered, Arnon, undated (Box 18)
      - Wagstaff, Christopher, 1984–2013 (Box 18)
      - Wakoski, Diane, 1964 (Box 18)
      - Walley, Gay, 1992-2011, undated (Box 18)
      - Watkins, Ben, 1998–2017 (Box 18)
      - Watts, Charles, 1994 (Box 18)
      - Waugh, Kyle, 2008, undated (Box 18)
      - Weinstein, Norman, 1981–1984 (Box 18)
      - Weiss, Mark, 2004 (Box 18)
      - Weston, Carol, 1984–2017 (Box 18)
      - Wigutow, Warren, 1981–1994 (Box 18)
      - Wilhelm, John, 1982 (Box 18)
      - Williams, Jonathan, 1968–1969 (Box 18)
      - Williams, Joye, undated (Box 18)
      - Williams, Kristine, 2016 (Box 18)
      - Wilson, Peter, 2003-2014, undated (Box 18)
      - Wodening, Jane, 1988–1996 (Box 18)
      - Wolosoff, Bruce, undated (Box 18)
      - Yarden, Elie and Nona, 1984–2017 (Box 18)
      - Yarden, Seth, 1986–2002 (Box 18)
      - Unidentified correspondents, 1955-2017, undated; 3 Folders (Box 18)
    - Family Correspondence
      Consists of correspondence of Gerrit Lansing, his mother Alice Scott Lansing, and other family members. Most of Lansing's letters to his mother were written while he was a student at Harvard, during his travels in Europe after graduation, and when he was living in New York in the early 1950s. Lansing frequently describes his efforts to network with editors, publishers, and other contacts in New York, and activities of his social circle, which included Kenward Elmslie, John McGavern, John Ashbery, anthropologist Dorothy Willner, and composer Elie Yarden.
      Not arranged in any particular order.
      - Letters to Gerrit Lansing from family, 1933–2018 (Box 19)
      - Letters from Gerrit Lansing to his mother, 1945–1952; 2 Folders (Box 19)
      - Letters from Gerrit Lansing to family, 1945; 1973 (Box 19)
      - Lansing family misc. correspondence [primarily postcards addressed to Gerrit Lansing], 1933–2018 (Box 19)
      - Letters to Harry Martin from Lansing family, Robert Kelly, Jean Radoslovich, 1960–1967 (Box 19)
  - Writings
    This subseries documents Gerrit Lansing's career as a writer and editor, and includes drafts, correspondence, financial records, notes, college papers, and printed materials.
    Organized into five groupings: Poetry, Notes and Notebooks, Early and College Writings, Other Papers, and Printed Materials.
    Associated materials: Writings by Gerrit Lansing can also be found in Correspondence, Occult Papers, and John McGavern Papers.
    - Poetry and Prose
      Drafts, proofs, correspondence, contracts and royalty statements, and other materials related to publication of poems, essays, and reviews or translations of others' works by Lansing. Included are files for his books Heavenly Tree, Northern Earth and Turning Leaves of Mind.
      Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
      - "Analytic Psychology, or Tracking the Soluble Whale," drafts, undated (Box 20)
      - "Analytic Psychology, or Tracking the Soluble Whale," proof, uncorrected, undated (Box 20)
      - "The Black Piano", undated (Box 20)
      - "The Chair of Light", undated (Box 20)
      - "Chimichanga Daze", undated (Box 20)
      - "The Clock of Roosters", undated (Box 20)
      - Contracts and royalty statements from North Atlantic Books, Poetry Foundation, 2008–2011 (Box 20)
        Related to Heavenly Tree, Northern Earth, and February Sheaf.
      - Correspondence regarding 2000 Parapsychology event (Box 20)
      - Correspondence regarding payment for publication, 1965–1966 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence regarding reprints of work by Lansing, Charles Olson, 1964–1972 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence with Paolo Javier, Alan Clinton, regarding 2nd Ave. Poetry, 2009 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence - invitations, solicitations to read, publish, 1967–1999 (Box 20)
      - Correspondence - rejection letters, 1959–1967 (Box 20)
      - "Day Book of Guy Legion", 1950s? (Box 20)
      - "Dreams", 1954–1977 (Box 20)
      - "Exposé of Vernal Occasioning", undated (Box 20)
      - February Sheaf printouts, undated (Box 20)
      - "The First February Book" [notebook], 1968 (Box 20)
      - "Fodor", undated (Box 20)
      - "Free Enterprise," typescript of play possibly by Kenward Elmslie, annotated by Lansing, undated (Box 20)
      - "The Good Friendship of Rocky and Enrico", undated (Box 20)
      - Hand-drawn map, related to fiction?, undated (Box 20)
      - Heavenly Tree Grows Downward
        - Copyright correspondence, 1966 (Box 20)
        - Disbound published copy, annotated (North Atlantic), 1977 (Box 20)
      - Heavenly Tree, Northern Earth
        - Table of contents, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 20)
        - Copies, proofs, undated (Box 20)
        - Printout, undated (Box 20)
      - Heavenly Tree, Soluble Forest
        - Table of contents, typescript, annotated, undated (Box 20)
        - Photocopies and printouts, with some corrections, undated (Box 20)
      - "Henry Thoreau and Cosmic Concord", undated (Box 20)
      - "The Initiation", undated (Box 20)
      - "The Living Doll", undated (Box 20)
      - "Lullaby for Loobies", undated (Box 20)
      - "Magnetic Fields of Desire", undated (Box 20)
      - Manuscripts - poetry and prose #1, 1960-2007, undated; 2 Folders (Box 20)
      - Manuscripts - poetry and prose #2, circa 1960-1991, undated; 2 Folders (Box 20)
      - Manuscripts - poetry and prose #3, undated; 2 Folders (Box 20)
      - "Mary Butts and the Dream of Badbury Rings," autograph manuscript notes, typescript, corrected, and clean copy, undated (Box 20)
      - Maximus to Gloucester foreward [typescripts, research material, book reviews], 1986–1991 (Box 20)
      - "A Measure of Gloucester", undated (Box 20)
      - "The Milk of the Stars from Her Paps", undated (Box 20)
      - "Mortlake", undated (Box 20)
      - "On Serial Painting: The Ambiguities of Thorpe Feidt", undated (Box 20)
      - "Ottilie", undated (Box 20)
      - Photocopies, cutouts, and proofs of published writings, some corrected, 1961–1993 (Box 20)
        Includes copies of Set.
      - Poems, typescript, addressed to Deryk Burton, 1961 (Box 20)
      - "Priest of Golden Apples: The Pagan Piety of Robert Herrick", 1960 (Box 20)
      - "Production as Metaphor, and 'Nature' in Baudrillard's Mirror", undated (Box 20)
      - "Psychic Invasion", undated (Box 20)
      - "Reckonings: Selected Poems, 1950-1959," typescript, addressed to Lansing's mother (Box 20)
      - Review of the Autobiography of Jack Woodford, typed draft and notes, 1962 (Box 20)
      - Review of Charles Olson by Tom Clark, 1991 (Box 20)
      - Review of Charles Olson's Reading by Ralph Maud, with unrelated (?) clippings, 1986 (Box 20)
      - Review of From Feathers to Iron by John Clarke, undated (Box 20)
      - Review of Gloucesterbook by Jonathan Bayliss, rough draft and notes, undated (Box 20)
      - Review of Melancholia by Clark Coolidge, 1987 (Box 20)
      - Review of Naked Lunch by W.S. Burroughs, undated (Box 20)
      - Review of Noble Traveller by O.V. Milosz, undated (Box 20)
      - Review of Portable Darkness, an Aleister Crowley reader, undated (Box 20)
      - Review of Selected Poems: In Five Sets by Laura Riding Jackson, 1970 (Box 20)
      - Review of Tufts University literary magazine, 1967 (Box 20)
      - "Riders All, Seas Deep", 1950s (Box 20)
      - "Robert Duncan and the Slipstream of Memory" [foreward], undated (Box 20)
      - "A Sense of Exclusion", undated (Box 20)
      - "Seven Events," co-authored with Kenward Elmslie, undated (Box 20)
      - "Shadows of the Evening", undated (Box 20)
      - Turning Leaves of Mind
        - Drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript printout, undated (Box 21)
        - Proofs, 2002 (Box 21)
        - Proof, with printer's markings, circa 2002 (Box 21)
        - Proof, limited edition, printed on Somerset Photo Enhanced papers, signed and numbered by the artists, 2003 (Box 30)
      - Typescripts - prose and poetry #1 [some annotated or corrected], 1958-2010, undated (Box 21)
      - Typescripts - prose and poetry #2 [some annotated or corrected], 1959-2003, undated; 2 Folders (Box 21)
      - Typescripts - prose and poetry #3 [some annotated or corrected], 1949-2002, undated (Box 21)
      - Untitled essay on history and metaphor, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 21)
      - Untitled John Josselyn essay, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 21)
      - "White Tractate on the Septenarius in Human Life for C.O.," typescript, undated (Box 21)
      - Word of Mouth [anthology]
        - Timothy Liu correspondence, 1999 (Box 21)
        - Lansing poem proofs, 2000 (Box 21)
      - "Wye", undated (Box 21)
    - Notes and Notebooks
      Consists of notebooks containing drafts of Lansing's writings, reading notes, notes and drawings related to the occult, and lists. Notes files sometimes contain personal information, addresses of friends or colleagues, and quotations.
      Arranged in chronological order.
      - R. L. Craycroft [notebook], 1938–1940 (Box 22)
        Includes transcriptions and translations from French of works by Haitian poet Clément Magloire-Saint-Aude.
      - Untitled notebook, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 22)
      - Lecture notebook [possibly class notes from Harvard], circa 1945-1949 (Box 22)
      - New England rarities - notes [notebook], circa 1945-1949? (Box 22)
      - Notes on poetry, 1946-2016, undated (Box 22)
      - Record I [notebook], 1951–1965 (Box 22)
      - Diary, 1958–1959 (Box 22)
      - Five-Year Diary, 1963 (Box 22)
      - Record II [notebook], 1963–1979 (Box 22)
      - Notes from untitled binder, circa 1970s (Box 22)
      - Notes on narrative, circa 1970s (Box 22)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1970s; 2 Folders (Box 22)
      - Weave [notebook], circa 1970s (Box 22)
      - Record II [notebook], 1976–2008 (Box 22)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1979; 2 Folders (Box 22)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1980s (Box 22)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1980s-1990s; 3 Folders (Box 22)
      - Notes on reading, 1983-circa 2000 (Box 23)
      - Untitled notebook, 1984–2000 (Box 23)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1986; 2 Folders (Box 23)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1990s (Box 23)
      - Elsewhere and Otherwise [notebook], circa 1990s-2010s (Box 23)
      - Felicity [notebook], circa 1990s-2010s (Box 23)
      - Olana or the Shark of Craving [notebooks], circa 1990s-2010s (Box 23)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1990s-2010s; 12 Folders (Box 23)
      - Untitled notebooks, circa 1990s-2010s; 2 Folders (Box 24)
      - Miscellaneous manuscript notes [writing, reading, language, personal], 1991-2017, undated (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebook, circa 1994 (Box 24)
      - Record [notebook], circa 1996 (Box 24)
      - Addresses and phone numbers, 1999, undated (Box 24)
      - The Clarified Butter of H.P.B. by G.Y.L. [notebook], circa 1999 (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebook, circa 2000-2010 (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebook, circa 2001 (Box 24)
      - Book lists, circa 2005, undated (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebook, circa 2007 (Box 24)
      - Record III [notebook], circa 2009 (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebooks, 2014 (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebook, 2015 (Box 24)
      - Untitled notebook, 2018 (Box 24)
      - Family tree of Peters family (previous owners of 207 Western Ave.), undated (Box 24)
      - List of female poets, undated (Box 24)
      - Notes for unwritten poem on P. B. Randolph, undated (Box 24)
      - Notes on Parmenides and Heidegger, undated (Box 24)
      - Recipes, undated (Box 24)
      - Transcription of Charles Olson's notes on fatherhood, undated (Box 24)
      - Poems written in 19th century account book, undated (Box 25)
        Journal and ledger of several Gloucester fish packing businesses, dated 1877-1881, in which Lansing wrote a number of undated poem drafts.
      - Phosphenes [notebook], undated (Box 25)
      - Untitled notebooks, undated (Box 26)
      - Untitled notebooks, undated (Box 27)
    - Early and College Writings
      Contains several high school papers by Lansing, term papers and short stories written while he was an undergraduate at Harvard, and his Columbia master's thesis.
      - Note folder of Gerrit Lansing, Park School, 1936–1937 (Box 28)
      - "Arrow" (literary magazine of the Park School of Cleveland), with contributions by Lansing, 1939–1942; 2 Folders (Box 28)
      - "Magic and Reasoning" [high school paper], 1945 (Box 28)
      - "On the Word 'Poetry'" [high school paper?], circa 1945 (Box 28)
      - "The Significance of Dayspring in 'Silex Scintillans'" [Harvard paper], 1948 (Box 28)
      - "The Vernal Wood by Thomas Norton" [Harvard paper], 1948 (Box 28)
      - "Description of a House Cat Sleeping on a Mountainside" [Harvard paper], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "The Interpretation of the Relation of Attribute to Substance in Spinoza" [Harvard paper], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "The Interview" [short story for Harvard English class], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "The Marvelous Heart" [short story for Harvard English class], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "Meaning and Interpretation in Literature" [Harvard paper], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "Nocturne" [autograph manuscript poem, Harvard era], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "William Butler Yeats and the Remarriage of Heaven and Hell" [Harvard paper], circa 1948-1949 (Box 28)
      - "The Easy Way Out" [short story for Harvard English class], 1949 (Box 28)
      - "A Moral Casualty" [short story for Harvard English class], 1949 (Box 28)
      - "On a Characteristic Image of William Cowper's: Sea-storm and Shipwreck" [Harvard paper], 1949 (Box 28)
      - "Transport to Metaphysics" [Harvard paper], 1949 (Box 28)
      - "Dogma and Natural Symbol in a Seventeenth-Century Vision: A Study of Henry Vaughan's 'Regeneration'" (M.A. thesis, Columbia), circa 1955 (Box 28)
    - Other Papers
      Contains autobiographical writings, translations, materials for readings, and tributes to other writers by Lansing, interviews of Lansing and reviews of his work, and a small amount of materials related to Abraxas Bookstore and Set magazine.
      - Abraxas Bookstore miscellaneous [correspondence, business cards, guide to identifying first editions], 1979–2013 (Box 28)
        Also includes holiday cards unrelated to the bookstore, which closed in 1992.
      - Autobiographical statements, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1945–1994 (Box 28)
        Includes a student paper from high school, and an autobiography of "Smoky Cleveland."
      - Autobiography: Harvard class of 1949 notes, 2004 (Box 28)
      - Imaginary interviews [self-conducted, including one with Ange Mlinko], undated (Box 28)
      - "The Imagination of Nature in North America," typescripts [lecture series], undated (Box 28)
      - Interview of Lansing by Edward Foster for Talisman, proof, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Interview of Lansing by Robert Podgurski, 2014 (Box 28)
      - Interview of Lansing by Patrick Doud, typescript printout, annotated by Lansing, 2015 (Box 28)
      - John Wieners "Oral History" [Lansing's notes and correspondence for Harvard panel], 2015 (Box 28)
      - John Wieners tribute in James White Review, 2002 (Box 28)
      - Library borrowing records, 2003–2017 (Box 28)
      - Manheim, Ralph, translation of "The Novices of Sais" by Novalis, typescript annotated by Lansing, undated (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous papers - fliers, clippings, cards, etc. [includes photographs], 1956–2016; 2 Folders (Box 28)
      - "Nature and Spirit in Recent American Poetry" [lecture by Lansing?], undated (Box 28)
      - Reading of Frederick Tuckerman poems, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Readings by Ken Irby - introductions by Lansing, 2002, undated (Box 28)
      - Readings by Lansing - fliers, etc., 1982–2010 (Box 28)
      - Readings by Lansing - introductions, set lists, preambles, 1978-2010, undated (Box 28)
      - Readings by Lansing - introductions by others, 2013, undated (Box 28)
      - Reviews of and essays about Lansing's work [typescript printouts, printed versions, correspondence], 1977–2015 (Box 28)
      - Robert Creeley tributes, 1988; 2005 (Box 28)
      - Set correspondence, prospectus, circa 1961-1998, undated (Box 28)
      - Set galley proofs, corrected by Deryk Burton, 1961-circa 1963 (Box 28)
      - Translations of Cesar Moro and Malcolm de Chazal poems, undated (Box 28)
      - Translations of Lansing's works by Nils Röller, Isabel Franco, and Jean-Paul Auxeméry, 1998–2016 (Box 28)
    - Printed Materials
      Consists of journals and books, broadsides, cards, and assorted ephemera, and newspaper clippings containing Lansing's writings.
      Organized into three groupings: Serials and Books, Broadsides and Other Printed Ephemera, and Clippings.
      - Serials and Books
        Contains anthologies, journals, and catalogues with poetry, reviews, and essays by Lansing, including New American Poets and International Journal of Parapsychology. There is also a published copy of his Analytic Psychology, or the Soluble Forrest is Swimming and Across, and an interview of Lansing in an alternative newspaper.
        Arranged chronologically by publication date.
        - Tomorrow: Does Man Survive Death? Symposium of scientific, religious and philosophic views on man's immorality, 1956 (Box 29)
        - Does Man Survive Death?, inscribed by Lansing to his parents, 1957 (Box 29)
        - "Mircea Eliade: Mythes, rêves et mystères," in The Review of Religion, annotated by Lansing, 1957 (Box 29)
        - "Liberazione e Rinascita," in Luce e Ombra, 1958 (Box 29)
        - "Physic Elements of Poetic Creativity," in International Journal of Parapsychology, inscribed by Lansing to his parents, 1959 (Box 29)
        - "In Winter her Body Still Nourishes Me," in Is., circa 1960s (Box 29)
        - "Planting the Amplitudes," in Trobar, 1962 (Box 29)
        - "Judgment of the City," in Trobar, 1964 (Box 29)
        - Three poems in Work, 1965 (Box 29)
        - "Destroy the Rice! A Victory Chant," in Work, 1966–1967 (Box 29)
        - Four poems in New American Poets, 1968 (Box 29)
        - "Stanzas of Hyparxis," in Inside Outer Space, annotated by Lansing, 1970 (Box 29)
        - "Weed Udana," in The Asphodel Book Shop Catalogue 27, 1971 (Box 29)
        - "Weed Udana" and "A Note on Some Literature of Wortcunning and Simpling," in Llama's Allmanac, 1972 (Box 29)
        - Five poems in Active Anthology, 1974 (Box 29)
        - Four poems in LOS, 1975 (Box 29)
        - "Stephen Phillips and the Warmth of Summer Nights," in The Thursday Book, 1975 (Box 29)
        - Interview of Lansing in Ann Other, 1975 (Box 29)
        - "Old & and new dependencies, good harbor," in Winter, 1979 (Box 29)
        - "Will Glen Burnie Never Pass Away?" in Daily Planet, circa 1980 (Box 29)
        - "The Welcome," in Text 12, 1981 (Box 29)
        - Six poems in America One [includes news clipping], 1982 (Box 29)
        - Analytic Psychology, or the Soluble Forrest is Swimming Across, 1983 (Box 29)
        - "The Package," in Oovrah, 1986 (Box 29)
        - "From Under the Mat Where Sat the Cat" [photocopy], in Cleveland, 1987? (Box 29)
        - "Reading My Life on a Greyhound Bus from Boston to New York," in No:tas, 1987 (Box 29)
        - Poems from "The Burden of Set #1," in Notus, 1991 (Box 29)
        - "Elegiac Fantasy, Delayed in Glass," in Notus, 1993 (Box 29)
        - Talisman: Gerrit Lansing Issue, 1995–1996 (Box 29)
        - "By Darklong River: In Praise of Frederick Tuckerman, 1821-1873," in Talisman, annotated by Lansing, 1996 (Box 29)
        - "Good Goo in Sooth" and "To Wee Virgins to Make Much of Time," in Mike & Dale's Younger Poets, 1998 (Box 29)
        - "How We Sizzled in the Pasture, in Mirage, 1998 (Box 29)
        - Tribute to John Wieners, in The James White Review, 2002 (Box 29)
        - "Blue Decrepit Town," in Underutilized Species [printed for the New Arts Festival in Gloucester, MA], 2005 (Box 29)
        - "Strolling Pebble Beach in February," in Process: prolegomena to the study of any future, 2009 (Box 29)
        - "Till Dawn's Early Light," in Polis, 2010 (Box 29)
        - "3 Poems of Giving," in The Portable Boog Reader, 2011 (Box 29)
        - "Sombre Fulguration," in The Emerald Tablet, 2013 (Box 29)
        - "A Few Admonishments for Funambuloes," in Kadar Koli, 2014 (Box 29)
        - "For Chance as Such, but Only as Such," in Matter, undated (Box 29)
      - Broadsides and Other Printed Ephemera
        Includes broadsides featuring Lansing's poems "Working in the Lower Red Field" and "The Bereft," among others.
        - Broadside and cards, 1980–2018 (Box 29)
        - Poetry broadsides, 1969; 2013; undated (Box 30)
      - Clippings
        - [Letters to the editor, reviews, and articles by Lansing], 1966–1998 (Box 29)
  - Occult Papers
    This subseries contains correspondence, writings, notes, research materials, charts, and other papers and objects collected by Gerrit Lansing related to the occult and astrology.
    Organized into two groupings: Occult Studies, and Astrology.
    - Occult Studies
      Includes correspondence, notebooks, writings, and printed materials concerning Lansing's occult research.
      Organized into two sub-groupings: Correspondence, and Other Papers.
      - Correspondence
        Contains incoming and outgoing correspondence of Lansing with editors, writers, and others involved in the Ordo Templi Orientis and occult and parapsychology studies.
        - Adamo, Ayesha, 2011 (Box 31)
        - Angoff, Alan, 1969–1971 (Box 31)
        - Babalon, Lola, 1990 (Box 31)
        - Bamford, Christopher, 1996 (Box 31)
        - Booth, Martin, 1969 (Box 31)
        - Breeze, Bill, 1990 (Box 31)
        - Crow, John, 1999 (Box 31)
        - Dorsso, Sven, 1990 (Box 31)
        - Draven, Douglas, 1997, undated (Box 31)
        - Disica 93, Fra. [secretary, Lastal Lodge of the Ordo Templi Orientis], 1979 (Box 31)
        - Ebon, Martin, 1956–1959 (Box 31)
        - Eliade, Mircea, 1958 (Box 31)
        - Evans, Jeffrey D., 1990 (Box 31)
        - Falorio, Linda, 1989–1990 (Box 31)
        - Feuerstein, Georg, 1984 (Box 31)
        - Godwin, Joscelyn, 1989 (Box 31)
        - Hammond, John Hays, Jr. (copy of letter to Eileen Garrett), 1959 (Box 31)
        - Kelly, G.M., 1992 (Box 31)
        - Martin, James, 1990–1999 (Box 31)
        - Perrin, Oliver, 1991 (Box 31)
        - Rosenberg, Andrew [photographs of art, poems], 2005, undated (Box 31)
        - Santucci, James, 2001 (Box 31)